# freesoul-kofi el shabazz-thompson

## education

northwestern university, evanston il mccormick school of engineering segal design institute

major: manufacturing and design engineering

graduation: september 2019

gpa: 3.1/4.0

bio

"I'm a designer, engineer, and experimental sculptor pursuing work in regenerative design. Born and rooted in Elmina, Ghana, yet growing up throughout the US tristate area has afforded me a cross cultural intuition de l'instant. Emergent from this is my interest in the design of institutions and systems, and how communities and cultures can be engaged differently to iterate on those institutions, structures, and products that impact their lives the most. The core of my work is about exploring and recreating relationships with nature in order to use all we have towards generating wholeness of experience for all.

## experience

cattle tech, evanston il design engineer (hardware lead) winter 2018 - summer 2019

"researched, designed, prototyped and tested software and hardware for virtual cattle containment for client *raitong organics* farm, sisaket thailand"

segal design institute, evanston il admin/design aide fall 2018 - summer 2019

"graphic design, administrative tasks and design/build projects for the department"

Ita research & exploration Ilc, mountain view ca engineering intern summer 2018

"research and design, rapid prototyping and manufacturing for lighter-than-air technology"

northwestern university, evanston il 'compass' peer mentor fall 2017 - summer 2018

"design of social events & workshops; peer mentor to "pod" of 4 compass students"

aon studios, chicago il media intern fall 2016 - winter 2016

"photographed, filmed & edited content for artists; co-produced interviews"

the heinz endowments, pittsburgh pa youth philanthropy intern summer 2015

"researched, created rfp's & design constraints—awarded \$25,000 to pittsburgh non-profit; produced blog, video and public radio project hosted at heinz.org"

#### www.freesoul.id

yes@freesoul.id ig@freesoul.id

+1 412 295 9517 +223 (0) 57 288 6471

pittsburgh, pa (usa) iture, elmina (ghana)

# skills

#### studio

3d printing injection molding shop (machine/hand) [cnc] milling (manual, hass) sewing

## programs

adobe photoshop adobe premier pro cad + cam (solidworks, nx) rendering (keyshot 8) ableton live arduino ide (learning) osx + windows factory apps

## computation

html, css matlab python git c++ (learning)

## language

english chinese (mandarin hsk2) fante (beginner)

#### soft

empath research design thinking growth mindset self-direction intercultural teammate

#### awards and support

resnick family fund (cattle tech) siemens nx design competition (northwestern university 2018)